And we're on in four, three,
two, one.
What if I told you that even the
worst neighborhood in America
could be made completely safe.
And what if I told you that
this could be accomplished
without risking the life of one
single law enforcement officer.
How do I know this?
Because it's happening right now in every
country in the world but this one.
I am Pat Novak, and welcome
to "The Novak Element".
In tonight's State of the Union segment
we will be joined by General Curtis Monroe
live from the War Room in the Pentagon.
General Monroe, welcome back.
Good to see you, Pat.
Thank you for this unprecedented
access to your operations.
Could you walk us through what we're seeing
here? Well, this is a routine operation.
We found that random patrols helped the local
population to feel safer and to trust us.
It's amazing. And what are these colored
dots that we're seeing here, General?
These are our assets on the ground.
In green, we got the ED-209s.
They're the big boys.
They secure the perimeter.
Purple are the smaller EM-208s.
They sweep and mop up.
And the red dots, Pat,
that's your film crew.
It is great to see American machines
helping to promote peace and freedom abroad.
All right, you guys, this is a standard op,
all right? There's no opposition expected.
I am going to set your
markers to code red.
All our drones are going to give
top priority to your safety.
No red assets have ever been lost. Okay?
Okay. Does that make you feel better?
But, listen, keep those bracelets on,
you're completely safe.
Okay? Good. Enjoy the show.
All right. Let's go.
May peace be upon you.
Please exit your homes with your arms
raised for a non-invasive scanning procedure.
No one will be harmed.
Please exit your homes with your arms raised
for a non-invasive scanning procedure.
No one will be harmed.
Scott, get me a shot of this.
Your co-operation is appreciated.
We apologize for any inconvenience.
May peace be upon you.
Incredible.
Incredible. Not long ago, that would
have been American men and women
risking their lives to pacify these people.
General, you care to comment on this?
Well, Pat, we had Vietnam,
we had Iraq, we had Afghanistan.
Never again. From a military
perspective, this has been invaluable.
We can accomplish our objectives
without any loss to American lives
and I think the honest people
over there really appreciate it.
And why wouldn't they?
For the first time in their lives they
get to watch their children grow up
in an environment of safety and security.
Navid!
Get away from the window!
Mom! They're here! They're coming!
Come here! Come here right now!
Arash!
Navid! You stay with your mom and sisters!
But he's just a kid.
Seven!
Stay here with your mom and the kids!
What do you think you're doing?
You heard me!
Arash, please don't go! Don't do this!
Navid! My dear! Come back here!
Navid!
Shut the door!
We're not here to kill any of them.
Got it?
The goal is to die on television.
Let's go!
Kelly.
Can you hear me out there?
Loud and clear, Pat.
I am here in sunny Tehran...
...where locals have clearly
embraced these routine scans.
As you can see behind me, they're working
in collaboration with the robots
and obviously their safety
is everyone's top priority.
Don't make a move before I say...
I wanna make sure they're recording.
Yes!
Yes! Yes!
We're ready.
You will notice children in the streets as well.
This is everyday life happening in perfect harmony.
Oh, great. Here, come here.
Stay put, stay put, stay put.
It's fine. Don't worry.
My guy's got it.
Navid! It's dangerous here!
Come away! Come...
Navid, where are you going?
Look at me! Navid! Navid!
What are you looking for? Navid!
Navid! Navid! What are you...
Navid! Don't go! Navid!
Oh, my God.
Drop your weapon.
Kelly?
Kelly. Are you all right? Kelly.
We're okay, Pat. Our robots have just
repelled some suicide bombers. Hold on, Kelly.
I am sorry, Kelly, but for security reasons
the Pentagon's going to cut our feed to Tehran.
But, please, be careful.
Yeah. I will continue to stand by.
Now you see how fundamental these
robots are to our foreign policy.
So then tell me. Why can't we use
these machines here at home?
Why is America so robophobic?
On the one hand, we have Raymond Sellars.
An entrepreneur and true American whose
product just saved my colleague's life.
And on the other.
Hubert Dreyfus.
A man with both feet
planted firmly in the past
whose bill prohibits the
use of drones on US soil.
The American people
support the Dreyfus Act
because they haven't experienced this technology
and they fear what they don't understand.
We at "The Novak Element"
support Mr. Sellars' efforts
to make our country and our viewers safer.
After all, what's more important than
the safety of the American people?
- Hey, Murphy.
- Hey.
How's Jack?
We don't know yet.
- Hey. Murphy.
- How's it going? Good.
What the hell are they doing here?
Six in the morgue. Lewis in the hospital.
This was the mother of all bad ideas.
We got a lead on Antoine Vallon, we took it.
What lead?
Not in front of them.
This is bullshit. Yeah?
Yeah, you got something to say, Murphy?
Vallon's our case. Yeah, two years without no arrest,
no nothing? You have got to be dumb or dirty.
You got something on us? Or is this
personal? No, it's nothing personal.
Although, I don't like you as a person.
Okay, you two, out. No problem.
Maybe if you hadn't gone off the reservation,
your partner would still be standing.
- What'd you say to me?
- Hey, that's enough.
Okay, Alex.
It's just you and me now.
So me and Jack, we have been doing some
street buys. We get a line on some guns.
We meet up with this
low-level G called Jerry
who ends up having a piece
he's not supposed to have.
Where the hell you get a
gun like that, Jerry?
I can get you two whole crates full, man.
Two crates?
No disrespect, J, but how a clown
like you get so much product, man?
What's it matter where it comes from?
Why it matters, we don't
want no dirty guns, Jerry.
These guns got bodies on them, Jerry?
Yo, look, they're clean, all right?
You going to buy this shit or not?
Hey, hey. Why you acting so nervous, man?
You fishing on us, Jerry?
What'd you say?
- You think he fishing, D?
- I think he's fishing on us.
Yo, what the hell are they talking about,
man? Hey, let me see your phone.
Let me see your phone.
I am not showing you my phone, man.
You recording this? What?
I think you're a goddamn cop.
What the hell are you talking about,
man? I am not showing you my phone.
Hey. Put your gun down.
Put your phones on the table.
We're not cops, all right?
We work for Antoine Vallon. What? Hey, hey.
Shut up. Shut up. What'd you say?
Ends up he works for Vallon.
Before the meet, we ran the
serial numbers on the rifles.
The guns were supposed to
be in our evidence room.
Not out on the street.
Intake papers blank. No signatures.
- What do you got?
- Nothing.
How do you think that happened?
I am telling you, Murphy,
this is a mistake.
These guys will shoot you just
to see if they gun work.
We need back-up.
If we call for backup, word's going to get
around the station. He's going to disappear.
It's going to be all right.
So we told Vallon we were gun
buyers, and he bought it.
What do you two need with that
much product? You plotting a coup?
Man, don't trip, we ain't going to
bust a single shot in your town.
We got some problems back
home with Chicago PD.
Yeah, I heard you don't like cops.
Hey, boss.
What do you got for me?
Really? We were just about to close the
deal but someone tipped him off.
Gentlemen, I got to deal with this.
Two minutes.
Make sure you kill them both.
I got two handguns, one automatic.
We got to get out of here. I am going
to take the automatic. You sure about this?
You ready?
Move.
Lewis.
Officer down.
Officer down, 331 Hamilton.
This is Detective Alex Murphy in need of
immediate medical assistance. 331 Hamilton Road.
Jack.
Jack, come on.
Jack. Can you hear me?
Jack. Stay with me.
Jack.
Alex, you don't do something like
this unless you bring it to me first.
Vallon's connected. I am warning you,
don't make any more moves until I vet this.
If officers are supplying him guns...
That's up to IAD.
I will handle it.
I don't care how sophisticated
these machines are, Mr. Sellars.
A machine does not know what
it feels like to be human.
It can't understand the value of human life.
Why should it be allowed to take one?
To legislate over life and death, we need
people who understand right from wrong.
What do your machines feel? Well, they feel
no anger. They feel no prejudice.
They feel no fatigue, which makes
them ideal for law enforcement.
Putting these machines on the streets
will save countless American lives.
You're evading the question. No, I am not.
Yes, you're evading the question.
I asked what do these machines feel?
If one of them killed a child,
what would it feel?
- Nothing.
- And that's the problem.
That's why 72% of Americans will not
stand for a robot pulling the trigger.
America is the world's most valuable
market, and we can't touch it.
With a domestic expansion, we'd
clear $600 billion per annum.
In other words, every second that law is
in existence, we are hemorrhaging money.
What do you want me to do?
We have thrown cash at senators at both
sides of the aisle. Nobody's budging.
They don't want to vote
against their constituents.
So unless we sway public opinion,
the battle's lost. Now, to that effect,
my team have come up with a
pretty aggressive new campaign.
Wow factor off-the-charts. We need to
give Americans a product they can love.
A figure they can rally behind. Sir, I have
dissected this bill. There are no loopholes.
We can't put a machine on the streets.
Forget machines. You saw the polls.
Americans don't want a machine.
They want a product with a conscience.
They want something that knows
what it feels like to be human.
We're going to put a man
inside a machine.
You're not you because of your legs, your arms,
your hands. You're you because of your brain.
It's your brain's capacity to process
information that makes you who you are.
Relax, and just do what
you have always done.
I have never played with these.
The music doesn't come from your fingers,
Michael, it comes from your mind.
All you have to do is let it out.
Please.
Oh, my God.
No, it's okay. Easy.
His emotions are peaking. The readings
are getting clouded. It's okay.
Relax. If you get too emotional, it will
change the chemistry in your brain.
It will throw the system out.
You're doing great. Come on.
I need emotion to play.
Concierto de Aranjuez, second movement.
Beautiful piece.
Dennett, when you have a moment. Thank you.
Now, we agreed on this a
long time ago, Raymond.
I wouldn't be asked to
develop combat applications.
My work here is driven by its own questions.
And your work is brilliant.
But your ideas are being underutilized.
Look, I think I found a way to put real
revenue stream behind your research and
save thousands of lives in the process.
You're not keeping up your end,
leaving me exposed like that.
Detective Murphy's just a little impulsive.
So put him on the payroll.
Why are we talking about this?
It won't work. And now that his partner
got hit, he's never going to let it go.
- What is that?
- Lewis' hospital.
Alex is dropping by this afternoon,
in case you want to send flowers.
Yeah. I kill a cop, looking over my
shoulder the rest of my life.
That's not good for business.
Who do you think's going to
be investigating you?
I am going to go hard after
Lake and Daniels.
I am going to have them in bracelets
within a month, man.
Hey, Vallon, I am walking up right now.
Cameras off?
Clear.
You were right.
We should have had back-up. I am sorry.
You're not really sleeping, are you?
Asshole.
Sergeant Thomas Ryan, NYPD.
Paralyzed from the waist down.
He has let himself go a
little since the accident. Pass.
Yeah. Yeah, fair enough.
Officer Alfred Miller, Denver.
"Severe Cerebellar..."
Cerebellar ataxia.
That's why you're the doctor, Doctor.
He scored through the roof
with our urban demos.
Let's keep this one in mind.
I like this guy.
Very good, sir.
I saved the best for last.
I give you Sergeant Jack
Freeman, masculinity incarnate.
Led Pittsburgh SWAT for five years,
now confined to a wheelchair.
I... think I can see the appeal. No.
What? Why? Well, check the psych evaluation.
He's far too unstable.
He's trying to say that he has a temper.
Have you any idea what we'd
be putting him through?
The psychological strain requires someone
emotionally balanced. We have to be scientific.
I mean, we're not selling a soft drink here,
are we? He's right. Okay. Keep looking.
David, what did I say? Not until
you're finished. Hey, guys. Hi, Dad.
- Hey.
- Hey, little monkey.
How's the game, buddy? Damon got ejected,
but we got a two-man advantage.
Oh, yeah? That's fantastic.
Hey, D, why don't you head upstairs
and start getting ready for bed.
But he just got home.
I will be up in a second.
Tuck you in, okay? All right?
- Now give your mom a kiss.
- Good night, baby. Too slow, boy.
You're just too slow.
How's Jack holding up?
They said a week till he's back on his feet.
It's my fault.
We shouldn't even have been there.
Here.
Oh, shit, I thought I fixed that.
It will stop.
It's going to wake up David.
He suffered 4th degree burns
over 80% of his body.
Lower spine has been severed.
If he survives,
he will be paralyzed from the waist
down and confined to a wheelchair.
Mrs. Murphy,
we don't have to do this.
I need to know everything
before I make a decision.
Please continue.
Vestibulocochlear, optical nerves
have been critically damaged.
He will be blind in one eye.
Most likely deaf.
Frankly, Dr. Norton and the Omni
Foundation are the leaders in this field.
In my opinion, this is the only chance your
husband has. I'd seriously consider their offer.
I am sorry, Doctor.
I need time to think. I am afraid, Mrs.
Murphy, time is one thing you don't have.
You say you can save him,
but what does that mean?
What kind of life will he have?
# Fly me to the moon #
# Let me play among the stars #
Thanks. Thanks, buddy.
You know she's going to make me dance again.
Now that I have got to see.
You don't want to see that.
Here she comes now. Hold on to that.
Get out there, partner.
Every time.
Get her, boy.
# Fill my heart with song #
# And let me sing forever more #
# You are all I long for #
# All I worship... #
Subject is still dreaming.
He's retrieving memories, trying to make
sense of sensorial stimulation package 37.
Perfect, Kim.
Let's reconnect the spine.
Time to wake him up.
# Fill my heart with song #
# Let me sing forever more #
# You are all I long for #
# All I worship and adore #
# In other words #
# Please be true #
Excuse me?
What are you doing here?
Baby, where you going?
# In other words #
Lewis.
# I love........ #
# You #
Subject regaining cognitive functions.
What's happening?
Where am I? You were in an explosion,
Alex. You're in a hospital.
Where is... Where's Clara? My wife. Where's my
wife? I want you to calm down, Alex. Listen to me.
You're okay. And your family's fine.
Both your wife and your son.
Who the hell are you?
I am Dr. Dennett Norton.
I am treating you.
"Heart rate" rising.
I can't move.
What the hell is all that?
Visual input unstable.
I want you to relax, Alex.
Subject's dumping too much epinephrine.
Should we purge it? Not yet.
Unlock vertebrae.
Go ahead, Kim.
Unlock upper, lower extremities.
What kind of suit is this?
It's not a suit, Alex.
It's you.
This was the only option. We're here,
all of us, to make you whole again.
Full body unlock.
I want you to walk now, Alex.
You can do that.
This seems so real.
Alex, it's very important you understand
what is happening. This is real.
It's not a dream,
it's not drugs or anesthetics.
I know I am dreaming because
I can feel all of this.
Alex, amputees can often feel their missing
appendages. It's called phantom limb sensation.
What do you mean "amputees"?
What the hell did you do to me?
You need to relax. Take this off me now.
You need to relax. I need to get out
of this thing. What did you do to me?
What have you done to me?
Alex? Hey.
Shut him down.
No. Let him run. Let him run.
Where am I?
Alex, please.
Stop.
Alex, you have to stop.
Please.
Alex.
Please stop.
Stay where you are and we will
come and pick you up.
Okay, Kim.
Shut him down.
Alex,
you can't run from this.
You have to understand the
reality of the situation.
Show me.
Kim.
Oh...
No.
Holy Christ.
Holy Christ, there's nothing left.
Your body may have gone,
but you're still here.
That's not even my brain.
We had to repair the damaged areas.
But we didn't interfere with your emotion or
your intellect. Do you understand me, Alex?
You're in control.
- I am in control?
- Yes.
Okay.
If I am in control,
then I want to die.
Just unplug whatever it is keeping
me alive and end this nightmare.
Now, say I did that.
Which as a doctor would almost be
impossible for me, but say I did.
What do I say to your wife?
What does she say to your son?
That it didn't work. That you tried.
Something went wrong.
You did everything you could, but,
I died. So after all they have been
through, all the pain, all their hope restored,
we would just rip that away?
Your wife loves you, Alex.
She signed the consent forms herself.
Otherwise, you couldn't have
undergone the procedure.
She loves you and she
gave you a second chance.
I need you to take it.
I don't want to see
myself like this again.
Ever.
And the same goes for my family.
Just put me back in.
Zoom in.
Stop.
Accept the connection.
It's so good to finally see you.
I was going to say the same thing.
I am sorry.
I know how I must look to you.
I think you look beautiful.
Are they treating you okay, baby? So far.
Dr. Norton, he seems like a nice guy.
Does David know you're calling?
He misses you.
- I can go get him.
- No.
I don't want him to see me like this.
Not yet.
Sure.
We're going to get through this, baby.
We're going to make it like it was.
When are you coming home?
Well, they have still got some tests.
But they're saying it's going really well.
The minute they let me.
I got to go.
I love you.
End the connection.
Okay, blood cleansing initiated.
Viral and bacterial screening activated.
Releasing proteins, fats,
minerals and carbs.
Energy inflow is at 1320 kilocalories.
Now starting anti-inflammatory corticoids,
hormones and antibiotic protocols.
Standard daily intake.
Release antidepressants.
Let's give him a nice dream.
All right, here's what you're dealing with.
Modified M2 battle rifle.
.50 caliber Beowulf ammunition at 30 round
clips. Three-shot bursts or full auto.
Heavy-duty.
TSR 66. Cartridge-driven taser pistol.
Each projectile releases up to 200,000 volts.
It can stun, it can kill and it's nasty shit.
Your armor, state-of-the-art,
but not invulnerable.
.50 caliber or larger
can penetrate and kill.
Multiple hits, and guess who
ends up in the recycling bin?
If you sense you need a
weapon or are threatened
the visor goes down and the system
makes the weapons available.
But you got to remember,
it's not the weapons that count.
It's who's handling them.
Or, in your case, what.
- You think you can do this?
- Oh, just stick to your job.
Just stick to my job?
Combat robots are my job, Doc.
Rio, Congo, you name it, I was there.
Our machines run perfectly.
You ask me, sticking organics into
the system is a huge step backwards.
I don't care how well you
designed this thing.
Without my sign-off, it better start learning
Chinese, because it ain't never going home.
It's nice to meet you, too.
Let's do this,
Tin Man.
Quality control, EM-208 versus Tin Man.
Rendering scenario one now.
Hey, Doc, hope you don't mind.
I like a little music while I am working.
# When a man's an empty kettle #
All right. All right, let's let the
games begin. Let's rock 'n' roll.
Commence scenario.
# Just because I am presuming #
# That I could be kind of human #
# If I only had a heart #
# I'd be tender, I'd be gentle #
# And awful sentimental #
# Regarding love and art #
# I'd be friends with the sparrows #
# And the boy who shoots the arrows #
# If I only had a heart #
# Picture me a balcony #
# Above a voice sings low... #
Lagging on the corners.
No, there, d'you see that?
What my robot did, that's how you do it.
New product's afraid.
2.3 seconds behind. Great.
Don't shoot. He has a gun.
Drop your gun.
Drop the weapon. Let the kid go.
Oh, well, it's worried that the kid's going
to get hurt. Let the kid go. Too bad.
Well, there you have it. 5.6
seconds behind. Scenario failure.
I wouldn't buy that for a dollar.
- Let's do it again.
- Your funeral.
Detective Alex Murphy.
Search results. "Detective Murphy
making a speedy recovery."
"Alex Murphy. Man or Machine?"
"Thrust into the spotlight,
Clara Murphy won't talk. "
Antoine Vallon.
Search results.
"DPD says Antoine Vallon no longer
suspect due to lack of evidence."
Detroit Free Press.
Unfortunately, Murphy's investigation into
Antoine Vallon wasn't authorized in the first place.
Look, Detective Murphy was
simply overzealous, okay?
We have absolutely no evidence linking
Vallon to the attempt on his life.
All I am going to say is my
partner's a great cop.
And I won't rest until the men who tried
to kill him are brought to justice.
What's wrong with him?
No, nothing, nothing.
Watch the procedural bars on the 208.
The machine assesses the threat and acts.
All right.
That's it.
It's two steps. Now watch Alex.
The software assesses the
threat, just like the robot. Yeah.
And it sends the information to the brain.
Alex's brain receives the information
and decides what to do with it
based on his emotional cognitive abilities
like any man would. Right. Right.
Then the brain relates this
to the Al module...
...and... Yeah, like, you know, a year later.
And our computers finish the job.
Raymond, you wanted a man inside a machine.
And that's what you have got.
But the human element will always be
present. Fear, instinct, bias, compassion,
they will always interfere
with the system. Okay, but, Dennett,
I have got to give the American people
something they can root for.
Something aspirational, right?
They have to believe in this thing.
"Pretty good"? That's not...
I don't know how to sell "okay."
We, you and I, have got a release
date, and we have got to make it, okay?
So I don't care how you do it. I am
asking you, come on, can you help me?
Just get him to do that.
Get him to do that. That is a machine.
I know, but it's a man inside a machine.
No, that's a man inside a machine right there.
And his life depends on it.
And the future of Omnicorp depends on it
so get your ass back to
China and get it fixed.
I don't care how you do it,
just go do it.
It tastes like peanut butter.
I can't get it out of my mouth.
And you don't like peanut butter?
No.
You like peanut butter, Kim?
I love it.
Okay.
I am going to put you
to sleep now, Alex. Okay.
Now, put him under, Kim.
What are you planning to do?
Consciousness is nothing more
than the processing of information.
I am going to fix him.
And he won't know the difference.
Raymond? Yeah? We just ran focus
groups at Ryan Correctional Facility.
We call this Combat Mode. It really put
the fear of God into the prisoners.
Yeah, that's okay.
And get a load of this.
- What's that?
- He transforms. Kids love it.
Really?
Focus group numbers through the roof.
- Really? Oh, yeah.
- Well, that's really embarrassing.
What is this? You know what?
People really don't know what they want
until you show it to them most of the time.
Make him more, uh, tactical.
Make him look, uh...
Let's go with black.
Yeah.
Alex.
He looks like a billion dollars.
2.6 billion.
Raymond Sellars. I have looked
forward to meeting you, Detective.
I really appreciate everything
you have done for me.
Well, we funded this program to
give men like you a second chance.
You just do your best today.
Shall we? Let's.
- Mr. Sellars, we're ready for you.
- Okay, great.
Chief Technician Shuman.
Morning, folks.
Okay, so this is how it's going to be.
We're going toe-to-toe.
Last man standing wins.
I hit you, you go back to the drawing board.
You hit me, you get a ticket back home.
My guys are going to be
shooting .47 caliber rounds.
Do a little damage,
but they can't take you out.
But make no mistake,
Tin Man, my gun will.
Alex, listen to me.
The EM-208s will try to maneuver you
so Mattox can get a clear shot.
Do not let that happen.
If Mattox hits you, everything but
your life support will shut down.
You will feel more pain than
you have ever felt in your life.
I don't know about that.
I have been through a lot.
All right.
I say we go on three. Three.
How's it going down there?
Whatever you do,
don't get shot in the face.
Wow.
Dr. Norton, how is he doing this?
His software is faster. His hardware
is stronger. He's a better machine.
But you said humans hesitate.
Only when they're making decisions.
He's not making decisions?
Yes and no.
In his everyday life, man rules over the
machine. Alex makes his own decisions.
Now, when he engages in battle, the visor
comes down and the software takes over.
Then the machine does everything.
Alex is a passenger, just along for the ride.
But if the machine is in control,
then how is Murphy accountable?
Who's pulling the trigger?
Well, when the machine fights,
the system releases
signals into Alex's brain
making him think he's doing what
our computers are actually doing.
I mean, Alex believes right
now he is in control.
But he's not.
It's the illusion of free will.
Crap.
So you have circumvented the law by creating
a machine that thinks it's a man.
But that's illegal.
No. No, no, no.
It's a machine that
thinks it's Alex Murphy.
And in my book...
...that's legal.
Well done.
Hey, Doctor, what happens if I tase an
exoskeleton with a little asshole inside?
I, uh, I think we're all
curious to find out. Go ahead.
If I had a pulse, it'd be racing.
She's been waiting four months.
I am sure hers is, too.
You're going to do fine.
I love your sign, D.
Hey.
There's nothing to be nervous about.
Thank you, Dennett.
It's been a privilege.
Hi, Dad.
You know I missed you, buddy.
Me, too.
Want to feel it?
What is it?
It's okay, sweetie.
I saved all the Red Wings
games on my computer.
You did?
How'd they do? I don't know.
I have been waiting to watch them with you.
You know I'd love to, kiddo.
But I can't tonight.
You know, because Daddy's
suit needs some...
Some special handling.
Do you understand?
Thanks for coming, Jack.
I heard you went home already.
I know Clara must be thrilled to have
you back. I saw Clara and David.
That ain't my home right now.
It's in a damn lab across the hall.
I am sorry, Alex.
Starting tomorrow, I am going to take
down Vallon and his whole damn crew.
I was waiting to hear you say that.
Least I know you're the right color now.
Pat, the cooler temperatures here today
certainly have not stopped
people from showing up.
We're expecting people from
every corner of the city
here in Detroit to come out and show their
support for Detective Alex Murphy.
You know, a lot of questions on people's
minds today is what will he look like.
Is he a changed man? Rumor has it he is
in the building preparing to come out...
Alex, we're going to upload the entire
DPD database into your brain.
That means you will have instantaneous
access to criminal records
plus an archive of CCTV footage
from 2011 to the present. All right.
Hit me.
Okay. Kim, it's all yours.
Archive footage uploading successfully.
Your system draws connections automatically.
It will link perpetrators to their crimes
and give you their exact
locations whenever available.
I got evidence to make
138... No, no.
166 arrests.
His emotions are stable.
This is incredible.
You will notice his family is
here in the building as well.
The mayor is standing onstage behind me.
Also, Raymond Sellars from Omnicorp.
They seem like great friends obviously echoing
the partnership that they have brought together.
How much longer will this take? Well, the
feed from the database is almost done, so.
We're approaching present day.
634 pending arrests.
We're going to need a bigger prison.
He's on top of her.
Dr. Norton, he's getting too emotional.
- I got to do something.
- Alex. Alex, calm down.
Take a breath.
Relax.
Kim, what are the readings?
I haven't seen him at levels like this.
- He's going to shoot them.
- Alex. Alex, Alex, relax.
Relax.
Alex?
What is this? This just a computer glitch?
No. That's his own crime scene. Alex.
He's spiking all over the place.
Alex.
Alex? The system is crashing, Doctor.
Alex, can you hear me?
Alex. Alex. I am not sure he can
handle this. I got to do something.
He's emotionally overloaded.
Unlock me. Alex. Stop.
Stop. He's having a seizure.
Kim, shut him down. Alex.
Get me a live feed. I can't do it.
Dr. Norton's with the patient.
Do it now. Jesus Christ.
- Dr. Norton. Dr. Norton. What?
- The press is waiting.
We have to get him up there now.
What do you want me to do?
I don't know. Fix him.
Do what you have to do.
Your reputation is on the line
every bit as much as ours.
We're running out of time.
Okay.
Everybody out.
Out.
Mayor Durant is about to take to the stage
and introduce Detroit's newest
weapon in the war on crime.
I am actually getting word that
he's ready to go right now.
Heart rate rising.
He might start spiking, Doctor.
Set modules to absorb
dopamine and noradrenalin.
But you will be taking away his emotions.
Drop the levels until I tell you to stop.
Doctor, you will be taking away his
ability to feel anything. Now, please.
Pull the footage. Put it on a loop.
Dopamine level's at 20%. More.
Dopamine level's at 10%. More.
Dopamine level's at 5%. Lower.
You're flattening him out. Lower.
- 2%.
- Hold it there.
Alex?
Alex, how do you feel?
I feel fine, Dr. Norton.
Well, today I am not here to
talk about crime prevention.
I am here to give you the cure.
That's right.
Hi, Dad.
Dad?
Ladies and gentlemen, the revolution
begins right now with Detective Alex Murphy.
Detective.
- What's he doing?
- He looks like a zombie.
I think he's accessing criminal data.
Thomas King. You are under arrest.
Until today, Thomas King was a convicted
felon wanted for rape, arson, and murder.
This man has torn apart
American families.
On the loose for six years.
And where was this criminal
mastermind hiding?
Right in front of the police headquarters.
Here he is, just steps away
from two of Detroit's finest.
These two officers are completely
unaware of the monster in their midst.
And then, in 60 seconds..... I repeat, just 60
seconds. You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say can and will be used against you
in a court of law. Detective Murphy brings him down.
You have the right to an attorney. If you cannot
afford an attorney, one will be provided for you.
This, my friends, is the
future of American justice.
How many like Thomas King will pay for
their crimes now that RoboCop is here?
Yes, let's not shy away from
what this means, people.
Men weren't up to the task.
But Alex Murphy,
a robot cop,
was.
We can't take him off the street.
This is what I am saying. He's a hit.
A big, fat, stinking hit. Yeah, until
he breaks down in front of everyone.
Hey, we all knew there would
be issues. It's inevitable.
Dennett, you're my guy. I just
need you to get a handle on this.
I know, but I need more time.
Scientifically, we're in uncharted water.
We need to take him back to
the lab and do more tests.
I mean, it was like something was
interfering with our system.
Something beyond chemistry or physics.
Like what? His soul?
Hey, look, this train has
already left the station.
I can't exactly go out to the world and say,
"Sorry, I released a defective product."
So, no matter what we do, we just need to keep
him on the streets. What about the interviews?
Cancel them.
Cancel all of them. Everything.
In fact, Dennett.
Let's.... Let's keep the wife at a
distance for now, as well.
I'd like to see him.
Can you arrange that?
Look, I won't lie to you.
Alex was so nervous, we had to sedate him.
I looked in his eyes and
I couldn't see my husband.
And then he just shoots a man in front
of our son. That's not sedation.
He's responding to drugs differently now.
We both knew from day one,
there would be complications.
Just give me a little more time.
I promise,
you will have your husband back.
This goes for every squad
in every department.
Detective Murphy will have full access to all
investigations. Robberies, narcotics, homicides.
If he requests to take over a case,
the case will be handed to him.
No arguments, no complaints.
This is bullshit.
I said no complaints.
And I mean it. Now...
Good morning, Chief Dean.
Good morning, officers.
I have selected 13 targets for
today, all wanted for murder.
John Biggs is target number one.
I will be taking over this case.
Ambulances, detention vehicles, and coroners
should be ready to move in on my request.
I wish you all a very good day.
Murphy.
You okay, man?
I am fine, Sergeant.
Can't wait to get back to work.
Lake and Daniels are in there shitting their
pants... Excuse me, I have casework.
Don't shoot. Don't shoot.
Walter Karrel, look at me.
You have two options.
Option one.
I shoot you with 50,000 volts which may
cause respiratory failure, organ malfunction,
internal burns, and loss of bowel and
bladder control. And then I arrest you.
Option two. You tell me where
John Biggs' drug lab is located.
And then I arrest you.
You have two seconds to decide.
Totally justifiable.
We are going to make a lot of money.
Nothing. No fear.
No increase in heart rate.
No traces of anger whatsoever.
Congratulations, Doctor.
You did it.
Yes, I did.
I told you, sir. Norton clearly
never had control of the product.
I agree.
And that's why I called you here.
I just want a second pair of eyes
on this thing, that's all. Okay.
I will need a feed from the Tin Man's head
plus full surveillance of the lab, and...
You're going to have full
access to everything.
If anything comes up,
I am going to be in Washington.
He brought peace to this country's
most violent city.
He showed us all that Detroit and
America can have a brighter future.
A future of economic growth,
freedom, and happiness.
On tonight's show, a visionary and true
patriot. The CEO of Omnicorp, Raymond Sellars.
- Hello, Pat.
- Raymond. Thanks for having me.
You must be doing a
victory lap about now. Well.
Two weeks ago, Omni's stock
went through the roof.
And the Senate has finally agreed
to vote on the repeal of the Dreyfus Act.
Well, look, I mean, the
tide is definitely turning. I...
I just feel certain that soon we will
be keeping all Americans safe.
I certainly hope so.
But, I think our next guest will have
a different point of view. Mmm-hmm.
Hubert Dreyfus.
Senator, thank you for joining us.
Hello, Pat. Mr. Sellars.
Senator, do you know what this is?
The American public is
divided on the Dreyfus Act.
Our polls at Novakelement.com
are tight at 50-50.
There is no doubt Omnicorp created a sensation
but this bill is not about Alex Murphy.
It's about whether America's willing to give
robots the authority over human lives. No. No.
Look, look, look. This sea change
we're witnessing, and it is a sea change,
shows that Americans don't really care if our
law enforcement systems are manned or unmanned.
What they care about is efficiency and they
care about safety. You're clouding the issue.
This is clearly an attempt to sway
public opinion with a marketing stunt. No.
What's clear is that with just one system
in place, we have cut crime by 80%.
Just imagine if we put, I don't know,
let's say 100 systems in place.
And then, I want you to ask yourself,
why are you holding us back?
Is that your plan? Thank you, Senator.
And thank you, Raymond. Thank you, Pat.
Well, there you have it.
Who could argue with that?
Which begs the question.
Has the US Senate become pro-crime?
Yeah, hi. No, no, 5000.
Call me tomorrow.
Hey, guys.
Vallon's waiting for you inside.
What, you too busy to walk us in?
I am out here making money. Yeah.
Where are my trip wires?
I got to do this myself?
- What took you so long?
- What the hell is all this shit?
I can't move any product with
this thing on the streets.
What are you doing to protect me?
Relax. The guy's a walking zombie.
And tell me your phones are off.
He's not going after you.
We covered our tracks.
He can't manufacture evidence out of
thin air. If he does, I am ready for him.
Well?
I have been getting calls. From whom?
Well, Clara. You need to let her
see her husband. She has rights.
That's not your decision.
That's Legal's call.
Yeah, but it's only a question of time
before she turns up on television.
Well, she can try.
I will issue a gag order before
I let her see her husband.
I'd hop to it.
Alex. Alex. Alex.
Alex. You need to come home.
Clara, please stand aside.
You need to speak to your son.
Right now, I see three crimes in progress.
Alex, listen to me.
I know you're in there.
David won't show his face at school.
He's having nightmares.
He's falling apart.
I am falling apart.
Please.
I can't do this on my own.
He's been scared ever since that night.
What do you think she's going to do?
What's he going to do?
Are you okay?
David? David.
Stand back. Come on, stand back.
He's supposed to be watching this.
Instead, he's accessing images of Clara and
David arriving at school. Over and over again.
Are you okay? Somehow, he's overriding
the system's priorities.
- Do you want me to shut him down?
- No. Not yet.
I want to see what happens.
What's he doing at his house?
Look, he's disobeying protocol.
You have to shut him down.
As far as I can tell,
he's still doing his job.
Adrian, give me an image of his brain.
He's undoing what we did to him.
His dopamine levels are coming back to normal.
How is that even possible?
I haven't the faintest idea.
Alex.
Alex, please return to the station.
I want to run some tests.
Well, this should be interesting.
And your phone on the table.
We're not cops, all right?
We work for Antoine Vallon.
- What? Whoa.
- What'd you say?
We work for Antoine Vallon.
My hand, man.
Where's Antoine Vallon?
You broke my hand, man.
I know you remember me, Jerry.
Where's Vallon? Wait a minute.
If I tell you where Vallon is,
he will kill my wife and kid, man.
Your wife left you in 2019 after
filing charges for domestic abuse.
And you don't have a kid.
But I do.
I am not asking again. Look, I swear, man.
I don't know where Vallon is, okay?
The only guy I talk to is his driver Marcus.
That's it, man. That's it.
Does he have a phone number?
We have a problem.
Alex is breaking protocol. What's he doing?
He's off solving his own murder.
Oh, that is genius.
Why didn't I think of that?
How long till he gets here?
Five minutes. All right.
Johnny, you stay on these monitors.
What happened?
Some idiot used an unencrypted phone.
Shit.
All right, everyone, listen up.
He's coming.
He leaves alive, you don't.
How do we stop him?
.50 caliber and above.
Aim for the head.
This one's set.
Let's go. Go.
All right, move. Let's go.
Come on. Come on.
Ready to go.
They're all set.
Finish it.
You freak, die.
Watch out.
Need me to call a doctor?
Come on, Jack. You're going to like this.
What the hell you doing here?
You all going to play good cop, bad cop?
Nah, Daniels. Bad cop, RoboCop.
I have recovered 26 guns
from Vallon's warehouse.
Thirteen serial numbers match
weapons missing from Evidence.
And I got your prints all over them.
This is bullshit.
I also have CCTV footage of you and
Vallon the same day he tried to kill me.
So put him on the payroll.
Why we talking about this?
It won't work. Now that his partner
got hit, he's never going to let it go.
What is that? Lewis' hospital.
Murphy's dropping by this afternoon.
I kill a cop, I am looking
over my shoulder...
You know what they do
to cops in prison, man?
Being locked up with the
same dudes you put in there?
How long you think
before he gives you up?
Don't shoot me. Okay?
I swear to Christ. It was Dean.
She helped pull those guns.
Just don't shoot me.
Thank you for your co-operation.
You can cuff him now, Jack.
Now I know why we couldn't get an arrest.
Because Vallon was protected from up on high.
Alex, I can explain.
You tipped him off today.
Come on, man.
Don't do this. You tried to kill me twice.
I trusted you. And you destroyed my family.
Confess.
Now, in front of everyone. Confess.
What happened?
Tin Man is down. Had to be done.
Why? Product shot a corrupt cop.
Two more seconds, the chief's brains would
have been splattered across the 6:00 news.
We got anything on her? Well, she's the
Chief of the Detroit Police Department.
What do you think?
You know what?
This might actually tip this
thing right into the net.
Alex, I don't know if you can hear me.
But tonight, you uncovered a nest of vipers
inside the Detroit Police Department.
And in so doing, you shed
light on an invaluable truth.
Even the police, the men and women who
swore to keep us safe...
...they can be bribed.
They can be bought.
Machines, however, are corruption free.
Americans could be living in a country
where law enforcement is not only efficient,
but incorruptible.
Thank you, Alex, for all you have done.
And for all that you are.
Detective Murphy is currently
in critical condition.
Our doctors are working ceaselessly
but, at this time, it is
unclear if he will survive.
Ms. Kline, Ms. Kline, how do you think
the attempt on Detective Alex Murphy's life
will affect tomorrow's
vote for the Dreyfus Act?
At this time, Omnicorp's sole concern
is the full recovery of Detective Murphy.
How many times does Detective Murphy
have to give his life for his country?
I sincerely hope the Senate
makes the right vote tomorrow
so that Alex Murphy's sacrifices
will not have been in vain.
Senator Dreyfus is my friend.
He has been my mentor and my strength
in times of difficulty on this floor.
But despite all that,
I work for the state of Ohio,
and the safety of its
citizens is my top priority.
So I vote yes.
The Dreyfus Act must be repealed.
That's us ahead, 39 to 10. I spoke to the
Senate liaison and it looks like it's in the bag,
but we still have to tread
carefully with the politicians.
We're here live at DPD headquarters
where moments ago, Clara Murphy made
a shocking statement. What the hell?
Omnicorp has denied me and my
son access to Alex for weeks.
I demand to know why.
This treatment is inhuman and somebody
needs to be held accountable.
Oh, we're fucked.
No, we only need 12 votes.
She shouldn't make much difference.
Yeah, but what about after the vote?
I mean, those two should
not be allowed contact.
If she starts putting ideas in his head...
Bring her in. I will handle the explanation.
And what about Alex? You know, unfortunately,
we can't just keep him on ice.
The shooting at the station
spooked some of the politicians.
They're our clients.
We have to take care of them.
They're fine when a machine
is lowering the murder rate, but,
when a man is investigating
city politics, they get nervous.
All right. First off, it's not a man,
okay? It's property of Omnicorp.
And politics are the least of your concern.
I mean, this thing solved its own murder.
How long till it realizes you
haven't been on the level with it?
If that happens, every journalist in
this country is dying to speak to him.
I mean, we created a hero.
What happens when he opens his mouth?
What's bigger than a hero?
Dead hero.
Get me Dr. Norton.
What is this, Raymond?
You have Mattox spying on me and now this
bullshit about a "critical condition"?
You know and I know Alex is fine.
Calm down. Dennett.
Your work is so good, I don't...
Well, now, this is not about my work.
You saw the woman on TV.
This has to stop.
You're right.
But let me ask you something, Dennett.
What kind of life have we
really given Alex Murphy?
He's never going to be a normal
man, a father, a husband.
By the time we put the other units
on the street, he's just... Dennett.
Let's face it.
We failed him.
We failed Alex Murphy.
But I want you to think about the bigger
picture because that's what we're talking about.
The work you have done with him is
going to be studied for decades.
You have changed the face
of history, Dennett.
No policeman is ever going to
die in the line of duty again...
...because of you.
You think about that.
I want that family taken care of
beyond their wildest dreams.
- We owe them that.
- I agree.
I want full funding. Ten years.
New staff, all my own people.
Fantastic.
Deal.
Hey. What's going on? Security's here.
They're clearing everyone out.
They're not waking him up.
Whatever you do, don't leave him alone.
What do you mean they're
not waking him up?
The voting period has ended.
The clerks have tabulated the results.
The yeas are 63.
The nays are 22. A majority of
senators have voted in the affirmative.
The Dreyfus Act has been
repealed by Congress.
God, you guys are slow,
like a bunch of girls. This is Mattox.
Bennett's on board.
It's about time.
Call it.
Get it done.
My pleasure.
- Mrs. Murphy...
- You can come here as much as you want.
You can threaten me. You can sue me.
You can take my home.
But I am not going to stop till I see
my husband. Do you understand that?
Mr. Sellars would very
much like to see you.
Is Alex okay? He has important information
to share with you. Will you accompany me?
David.
We got to go.
Can you grab your coat?
Hey. I am in the elevator,
on my way down. I need access to the lab.
That's insane. They're still here.
Distract them. Okay.
I cannot...
There's a lady in here going hysterical.
She will not let us in.
She's got the codes for the door.
I repeat, she will not let us in.
Lady, you need to let us in there now.
We have to get in there.
Are you not understanding
what I am saying?
Do you want to be responsible for the deaths
of everyone in this building? Hey. Stop.
Don't shoot.
Step outside.
Unlock the transmitter.
Transmitter unlocked.
Send in Mrs. Murphy, please.
Right away, sir.
Wake him up.
Alex. Alex.
Alex, it's Dr. Norton, you have to wake up.
Alex, can you hear me?
These men are here to kill us.
They're here to kill us, for chrissakes.
Mrs. Murphy, last night,
Alex had a psychotic break.
He killed an unarmed colleague
and later suffered a seizure.
We did everything, everything, we could,
but the doctors couldn't save him.
Very sorry, Mrs. Murphy.
We're going to be making
the announcement shortly.
You shut me down.
I was about to get a confession.
Mattox shut you down.
I have removed your transmitter
so he won't do it again.
Sellars can't afford to wake you up.
He sent these guys to pull the plug.
He wants you dead, Alex.
Do you understand?
Sorry. If there's anything we can
do for you and David, we will do it.
I want nothing from you.
I understand.
You stay out of our lives.
You and your company.
If that's what you think is best.
There's one more thing.
I think it would be to the benefit of everyone,
especially David if we kept this matter private.
We don't want to damage Alex's legacy.
Alex. Alex. Alex.
I can fix this.
You lied to me.
You lied to my wife. You're working for
the people that are trying to kill me.
You want me to trust you, Doctor?
Alex, I can go to the press.
Alex, I can tell them the whole story.
Alex.
Listen to me, please.
Alex. Alex.
What the hell?
Keep all our systems at green and for
chrissakes, get Sellars on the phone.
Roger that.
Damn, damn, damn, damn, damn.
Look at this city.
So beautiful.
It's become so peaceful.
I wish
I had some good news for Detroit.
I have very sad news.
Despite our best efforts to save him,
Alex Murphy passed away just hours ago.
Alex Murphy was... Mr. Sellars.
- What is it?
- Mattox just called.
We need you to come with us now.
Ma'am, I need you to turn around
and go the other way, please.
- What are you talking about?
- We have a security situation here.
I need you to turn around
and go the other way.
Sir, there's a car outside that's supposed
to... That area is locked down. Now go.
- What's happening?
- I said go.
I want to talk to Mr. Sellars.
Mr. Sellars. How close is that helicopter?
About 10 minutes, sir.
Excuse me. Yes? I need to speak with
Sergeant Jack Lewis.
It's an emergency.
Stand by. Mr. Sellars.
Apparently there's a Clara
Murphy in the lobby.
Raymond, if she sees him,
we are dead in the water.
- What do you want to do?
- Bring Mrs. Murphy up here. Yes, sir.
Norton said they may be using
drones for protection.
So whatever you do,
do not draw your weapons.
They won't shoot if we're unarmed.
Clear? Clear. Clear.
Hold it right there.
Don't move.
This is private property.
You are not authorized to be here.
I'd put those guns down now if I were you.
Stand down. All right, man, we're good.
Back it up.
Head to the lower level.
- Hold up, hold up.
- Ram it.
Gun it.
Go. Go, go. Now.
Alex, run.
Omnicorp Security.
Drop your weapons. Drop your weapon.
Keep your hands above your head
and no one will be harmed.
What's going on? Mrs. Murphy,
I want you to listen to me carefully.
The organic part of your
husband Alex is dead.
The robotic part of him is malfunctioning,
and he's shooting up the building.
So we have got to get you and your
son out of here right away.
I got to take this call.
He just left the lobby and he's headed
our way. Roger that, sir.
- Don't shoot. My robot. You just flank.
- Got it. Tin Man.
Tin Man.
Oh, there it is.
You look like crap.
What's the matter?
Can't shoot?
Huh?
What were you thinking?
This isn't a drill. You're a robot.
I am a red asset. Wrote that myself.
What do you think?
Come on, Tin Man, just pull the trigger.
Pull it.
You can run.
Go on.
Run.
There you go. Run.
Run. Run.
Whoo.
Stings like a bitch, don't it?
Aren't you lucky I didn't
have my gun set to "kill"?
Hey, listen.
This isn't personal.
Well, maybe a little.
I am going to put you
out of your misery.
Helicopter's approaching.
Mr. Sellars boards first.
No, no, no. Mrs. Murphy, you
and your son can get on first.
Officer down.
Mechanical room.
Omnicorp Building.
Roger that. EMS on the way.
You're going to be okay, Jack.
It's nonfatal. Go. Go.
Omni-LZ Helo-1 on approach to deck.
What's that?
- He's got a gun.
- What? Pull up. Pull up.
- What the hell is he doing?
- Sorry, sir. I don't know.
Alex?
Dad?
Clara, David.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Wait.
- Get out of the way.
- Alex, put down the gun.
Clara, take David and
get out of the way now.
Raymond Sellars, you're under arrest
for the attempted murder of a police officer.
Are you here to cuff me? All right.
Go ahead, cuff me. You can't.
You're not programmed that way.
If you go against the program,
the entire system shuts down, so.
You don't even have a warrant.
We will overlook this little...
Get down on the ground and put
your hands behind your back.
I am just from marketing.
Now. Okay, yep, yep, yep. Yep.
Alex, we need to work together here.
Because I am the only one with the
technology to keep you alive.
Dead or alive, you're coming with me.
All right.
Weapon.
Alex, honestly, I mean you no harm.
If I wanted to, I could have
killed you a long time ago.
I just aim this right at your head and
blow it off. Sellars, please. Don't.
I mean, if I wanted to, I could
just aim this at your little family
and I could just kill them too.
And really, there's nothing you could
do about it because, let's face it,
you're a robot.
Do you understand that?
Alex.
Dad.
Baby.
Hey.
Everything's going to be all right.
How you feeling, Alex?
I am ready.
He's ready.
There's still no word from
Omnicorp parent company, OCP.
And although the government says
they are rebuilding Alex Murphy,
rumors continue to swirl
about his condition.
But we have obtained exclusive
video taken by cell phone
that shows the people of Detroit may
have Alex Murphy back on the streets
sooner than they think.
The real tragedy here is that our
president chose to uphold the Dreyfus Act.
Now, I have no doubt he was
manipulated by our biased media
and by whistle-blower Dennett Norton.
I acknowledge we know
less than we thought.
But I do believe my
research program is sound.
What I did with it
was wrong.
The fact that this mother...
is not serving time in some federal penitentiary
is a huge, hot, heaping pile of horse...
Now I know some of you may think that
this kind of thinking is dangerous
and these machines violate
your civil liberties.
Some of you even believe that the
use of these drones overseas
makes us the same kind
of bullying imperialists
that our forefathers
were trying to escape.
To you, I say...
Stop whining.
America is now....
...and always will be...
...the greatest country on
the face of the Earth.
I am Pat Novak.
Good night.